# SRISHTI YADAV

I am a machine learning engineer engineer with primary experience in computer vision based applications. In past I was a graduate research (Masters) at Simon Fraser University, Canada. I have worked with semi-supervised learning and class-imbalance problems. I have experience in implementing machine learning algorithms at scale.

#### **SKILLSET**

Software: MATLAB, Octave

Languages and Tools: PyTorch, Python, Numpy, Scipy, OpenCV, Matplotlib, Docker, AWS cloud services like S3, EC2 and Amazon Sagemaker as well as Azure services like Datalake, AML and Azure functions.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Master of Applied Science (Computer Vision)

Simon Fraser University, Canada, January 2021 CGPA: 3.92/4.33

Bachelor of Technology, Electronics and Communication

Uttar Pradesh Technical University, India, June 2016

#### **PROJECTS**

### Predictive Domain Analysis using CLIP

- Used CLIP model and its text embeddings to find similar images.
- Used zero shot learning on DomainNet dataset with CLIP to find closest domain for unseen samples.

# RGB-Depth Based Occlusion Aware Target Re-detection Video:

- Implemented target re-detection long term tracker using Kinect RGB-D camera.
- Tracker was able to infer & track target with information provided only in first frame.
- Improved average precision by almost 50% as compared to baseline KCF tracker

# Deep Attention Models for Human Tracking Using RGBD | Paper:

- Worked in a team of 4 to develop an adaptive appearance model to accurately detect color camouflage, even in the presence of complex natural objects.
- Improved the accuracy by approximately 50% and reduced the type I error by 23% and type II error by 5%.

#### Celestini Project India:

- At Samsung IoT Lab, developed a prototype video analytic algorithm using Caltech pedestrian dataset to run on Raspberry Pi 3 Model B.
- Worked in a team of 2 where I was responsible for porting the code from MATLAB to Octave. Also, worked on pre-processing the data to clean images, remove noise to infer position, lane and density of vehicles in front of the camera.

# Prototype Landslide Risk Communication System Paper:

- Developed a system which forecasts and communicates occurrence of landslides.
- Conducted field survey and implemented a system for sensor deployment (sensors, microcontroller boards, GSM module and other electical components).

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Machine Learning Engineer

(currently working)

Cubic Farms, Canada

- Research, develop, and implement ML algorithms into a variety of data ingestion sources for imagery data and IoT data
- Design and implement ML models that scale to thousands of machines Also package tests, build containers and deploy artifacts in CI/CD pipelines

#### Machine Learning Consultant

July 2021-August 2021

- Computed and analyzed vegetation index for plant health from aerial raster data.
- Worked on a data pipeline leveraging Deep Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) to segment individual plants in orthomosaic raster imagery.
- Worked on plan detection for high-value crops that need to be monitored at the resolution of individual plants

### Machine Learning Researcher

February 2021-June 2021

MILA, Montreal, Canada

- Worked on large scale time-series dataset in the order of millions of data.
- Implemented and scaled data pre-processing to run on cloud; cleaned data into standardized format.
- Tested data for ordinal classification problem for data modelling and processing geospatial (satellite) data.

### Machine Learning Intern

February 2020-August 2020

UrtheCast, Vancouver, Canada

- Individually implemented machine learning system for satellite data (Landsat8, SPARCS, Sentinel 2 dataset) for multi-class prediction of cloud, shadow, and haze.
- Implemented data ingestion pipeline which takes in raw geospatial multi-dimensional data as input and converts it into standardized format.
- Scaled the algorithm using AWS cloud based services, example, EC2 for deployment server, S3 for data storage and docker for creating virtual environment and parallel deployment of multiple training jobs.
- Investigated and implemented optimization methods to improve cloud mask generation from S2 data using the Green, Red Edge, and Water Vapor band.

### Graduate Research Assistant

January 2018-February 2021

Networked Robotics and Sensing Laboratory
School of Applied Science, Simon Fraser University, Canada

#### Project Associate

August 2017-October 2017

Helicopter and VTOL Laboratory
Indian Institute of Technology Kanpur, India

### Computer Vision & IoT Developer

June 2016-July 2017

Samsung IoT Innovation Lab, Delhi, India & Applied Cognitive Science Lab, India

#### **PUBLICATIONS Book Chapter**

Chaturvedi, P., Thakur, K., Mali, N., Kala, V. U., Kumar, S., Yadav, S. & Dutt, V. (2017). A Low-Cost IoT Framework for Landslide Prediction and Risk Communication. In CRC Press: Internet of Things Concepts, Technologies, Applications, and Implementations (2017)

#### Journals

Yadav, S., & Payandeh, S. (2021). Critical Overview of Visual Tracking with Kernel Correlation Filter. Technologies, 9(4), 93.

Rasoulidanesh, M., **Yadav, S.**, Herath, S., Vaghei, Y., & Payandeh, S. (2019). Deep Attention Models for Human Tracking Using RGBD. Sensors, 19, 750. (Poster at WiML Workshop, **NeurIPS 2019**)

[Thesis]Yadav, S. (2021). Occlusion Aware Kernel Correlation Filter Tracker using RGB-D. arXiv preprint arXiv:2105.12161.

# OUTREACH

- Computer Vision Interest Group@ML Collective

Co-organizer

- Women in Computer Vision (WiCV) @CVPR 2021 (Virtual)

Advisor

- Women in Computer Vision (WiCV) @CVPR 2020 (Virtual)

Organizer

- Women in Machine Learning @NeurIPS 2019 (Vancouver, Canada)

 ${\bf Organizer}$ 

- Invent the Future, AI4ALL@SFU (Vancouver, Canada)

Mentor(Robotics)